Finding Aid for Ralph W. Muncy papers, ca. 1830-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ralph W. Muncy papers circa 1830-1992
Muncy, Ralph W. (Ralph Waldo), 1902-
(in 16 boxes)
15.5 linear feet
85535 Aa 2
Socialist Labor Party member, later member of the League for Socialist Reconstruction. Correspondence, campaign files, audio-tapes, and other materials largely concerning his work with the State Central Committee of the Socialist Labor Party and Socialist Reconstruction, 1928-1992; and collected family materials including letters and memoirs of Levi Muncy, soldier during the Civil War; also photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers of Ralph Muncy (donor no. 4010 ) began coming to the library in 1963.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Ralph Muncy, socialist, educator, forester, civil engineer, and avid genealogist, was born April 26, 1902 in Cedar, Michigan, the son of John Irvin and Maud Ackley Muncy. After graduating from Ann Arbor High School in 1919, Muncy received a bachelor's degree in forestry from the University of Michigan in 1923. In 1930, Muncy received a teaching certificate from the University's School of Education. Best known for his ardent activities, Muncy was a member of the Socialist Labor Party (1930-1970) and later as a member of an offshoot party known as the Industrial Union Party (1970-1992). Muncy's sympathies for the working class were planted early. In the 1920s, his father, an automotive engineer, took young Ralph into the Studebaker plant in Detroit where he worked. While normally a soft spoken man, his father shouted and cursed at the workers, explaining to Ralph that this was the only way to treat the men. This episode made a lasting impression on Muncy.
Muncy, between 1952 and 1970, served as both secretary and chair of the Socialist Labor Party (SLP). Eventually disillusioned with the SLP because he believed that the party was diluting its program and 'cozying up' to capitalism, Muncy left the party in 1970 and was instrumental in the founding conference, in Ann Arbor, of Socialist Reconstruction (reorganized in 1981 as the Industrial Union Party). The membership of this new party consisted of former members of the S.L.P. and others who subscribed to Socialist Industrial Unionism as the foundation of a new society and form of government based upon public ownership of the means of production.
During his tenure as a member of each party, Muncy ran unsuccessfully for various state offices including Governor (1956 and 1982), Attorney General (1954 and 1960), Secretary of State, Highway Commissioner (1957), and Superintendent of Public Education. Muncy also ran for the U.S. Senate in 1966 and the U.S. Congress in 1968. Muncy wrote extensively on socialism and contributed to various socialist publications, as well as to a number of Michigan and national newspapers. He also lectured on socialism in CCC (Civilian Conservation Corps) camps during the 1930s.
Muncy's wife, Lydia Baird Muncy, born February 10, 1902 in Marine City, Michigan was the daughter of William Baird and Grace Low Baird. She shared her husband's interest in the socialist cause. Besides running on the party ticket for a position on the Board of Regents of the University of Michigan in 1968, Lydia Muncy was an active speaker appearing as a guest lecturer for such groups as the League of Women Voters on several occasions.
In addition to his activities with the Socialist Labor Party and the Industrial Union Party, Muncy practiced forestry as a private consultant and as an employee of the United States Forest Service until 1940. Subsequently, he was engaged as a civil engineer, in which capacity he was employed by General Motors, the Great Lakes Steel Corporation, and McNamee, Porter & Seeley Civil Engineering of Ann Arbor.
Muncy was also an avid genealogist and researched his own family genealogy extensively. He belonged to a number of historical societies including the Washtenaw County Historical Society (Mich.), the Historical Society of Michigan, and the Thomas Minor Society. Muncy was in charge of the newsletter for the Washtenaw County Historical Society and gave some lectures at the Society. Muncy also served as the historian for his Ann Arbor High School class and edited an alumni newsletter. Ralph Muncy died in March 1992, at the age of 89.
The Ralph Muncy collection consists primarily of papers relating to his interest in socialist political activities. A smaller portion of the collection documents the involvement of his wife, Lydia B. Muncy, in the socialist cause. Together they also collected materials relating to the history of their families (Muncy-Baird). Included is much original family material dating back into the nineteenth century. The Ralph Muncy papers have been arranged into the following series: Correspondence; Topical Files; and Ralph Muncy and Lydia Baird Muncy Personal.
Subjects:
Baird family.; League for Socialist Reconstruction (U.S.); Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Michigan--Politics and government--1939-1945.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Muncy, Levi.; Muncy, Ralph W. (Ralph Waldo), 1902-; Muncy family.; Radicalism--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Socialist Labor Party.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States--Politics and government--1963-1969.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor High School (Mich.); Ann Arbor High School (Mich.). Class of 1915.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dams.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Streets.; Argo Dam (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Automobiles.; Atikokan (Ship); Bach School (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Baird family.; Camp Davis (University of Michigan); Classrooms.; Coffins.; Dams--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Grand Haven (Mich.); Interiors.; Laborers.; League for Socialist Reconstruction (U.S.); Marine accidents.; Marine City (Mich.); Muncy, Lydia B. (Lydia Baird); Muncy, Ralph W. (Ralph Waldo), 1902-; Muncy family.; Music--Michigan.; Parades and processions.; Perry School (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Political parties.; Rural schools.; Schools--Michigan--Superior (Washtenaw County: Township); Schools--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Sheep.; State Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Streets--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Socialist Labor Party.; Superior (Washtenaw County, Mich.: Township); Tappan School (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Teachers--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; University of Michigan. Class of 1923.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1911-1920.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1921-1930.; White House Conference on Education (1955: Washington, D.C.); Women.; Women--Organizations.
Contributors:
Muncy, Lydia B. (Lydia Baird)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series has been divided into two subseries: by date and by name of correspondent. The correspondents were largely individuals associated with Muncy while active first with the Socialist Labor Party and then the Socialist Reconstruction Party. The researcher should note that there is considerable overlap between the chronological and subject correspondence files and should thus consult each of the subseries.
  - Chronological
    - 1928-1935 (Box 1)
    - 1936 (Box 1)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 1)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 1)
    - 1941-1943 (Box 1)
    - 1944 (Box 1)
    - 1945 (Box 1)
    - 1946 (Box 1)
    - 1947 (Box 1)
    - 1948 undated January-February 1948 (Box 1)
    - March-April 1948 (Box 1)
    - May-August 1948 (Box 1)
    - September-December 1948 (Box 1)
    - 1949 undated January-March 1949 (Box 1)
    - April-June 1949 (Box 1)
    - July-October 1949 (Box 1)
    - November-December 1949 (Box 1)
    - 1950 undated January-March 1950 (Box 1)
    - April-May 1950 (Box 1)
    - June-July 1950 (Box 1)
    - August-December 1950 (Box 1)
    - 1951 (Box 1)
    - January-July 1952 (Box 1)
    - August-December 1952 (Box 1)
    - 1953-1955 (Box 1)
    - January-May 1956 (Box 1)
    - June-August 1956 (Box 1)
    - September 1956 (Box 1)
    - October-December 1956 (Box 1)
    - 1957 undated January-June 1957 (Box 1)
    - July-December 1957 (Box 1)
    - 1958 undated January-June 1958 (Box 1)
    - July-December 1958 (Box 2)
    - 1959 undated January-June 1959 (Box 2)
    - July-December 1959 (Box 2)
    - 1960 undated January-June 1960 (Box 2)
    - July-August 1960 (Box 2)
    - September-October 1960 (Box 2)
    - November-December 1960 (Box 2)
    - January-March 1961 (Box 2)
    - April-December 1961 (Box 2)
    - 1962 undated January-March 1962 (Box 2)
    - April-August 1962 (Box 2)
    - September 1962 (Box 2)
    - October-December 1962 (Box 2)
    - 1963 undated January-March 1963 (Box 2)
    - April-December 1963 (Box 2)
    - 1964 undated January-April 1964 (Box 2)
    - May-July 1964 (Box 2)
    - August-September 1964 (Box 2)
    - October-December 1964 (Box 2)
    - 1965 undated January-March 1965 (Box 2)
    - April-August 1965 (Box 2)
    - September-December 1965 (Box 2)
    - 1966 undated January-March 1966 (Box 2)
    - April-July 1966 (Box 2)
    - August-September 1966 (Box 2)
    - October-December 1966 (Box 2)
    - 1967 undated January-June 1967 (Box 2)
    - July-December 1967 (Box 2)
    - 1968 undated January-May 1968 (Box 2)
    - June-August 1968 (Box 2)
    - September-December 1968 (Box 2)
    - 1969 (Box 2)
    - 1970 (Box 2)
    - 1971 (Box 3)
    - 1972 (Box 3)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 3)
    - 1975-1980 (Box 3)
    - 1981-1984 (Box 3)
    - 1985-1987 (Box 3)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 3)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 3)
    - Undated (Box 3)
  - Name files
    - Administrative Council (Box 3)
    - Allen, Francis (Box 3)
    - Ann Arbor Chapter 1971-1983 (Box 3)
    - Bates, Henry 1973-1983 (Box 3)
    - Begovich, John 1974-1980 (Box 3)
    - Begovich, John and Margaret 1986 (Box 3)
    - Bell, Frank (Box 3)
    - Bentley, Elsie 1972 (Box 3)
    - Bentley, W. Clifford 1956; 1965-1966 (Box 3)
    - Block, Murray 1973-1981, 1983-1987 (Box 3)
    - Brandon, Sam (Sec'y. of the Daniel DeLeon League branch, N.Y.)
      - January-June 1970 (Box 3)
      - July-December 1970 (Box 3)
      - 1972 (Box 3)
      - 1973-1976 (Box 3)
      - 1977-1981 (Box 3)
      - 1982-1985 (Box 3)
      - 1987-1991 (Box 3)
    - Brinning 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - British Comrades 1983; 1985-1986 (Box 3)
    - Brockway, Darrell
      - 1969-1971 (Box 3)
      - 1972-1981 (Box 3)
    - Burlingame, R. F. 1983 (Box 3)
    - Collins, James 1971-1980 (Box 3)
    - Deck, Martin 1974-1976 (Box 3)
    - Detroit Chapter 1971 (Box 3)
    - Diamond, Julien 1972-1976 (Box 3)
    - Dixon, Richard 1980 (Box 3)
    - Ferguson (Box 3)
    - Forsyth, Ralph (National Secretary Socialist Reconstruction) 1970-1972 (Box 3)
    - Frank, Paul Robert 1971 (Box 3)
    - Friedrichs, Debbie 1987 (Box 3)
    - Gardner, Jigs (member of National Administrative Council
      - Undated (Box 3)
      - 1970 (Box 3)
      - January-March 1971 (Box 3)
      - April-December 1971 (following resignation from party) (Box 3)
      - 1971-1973 (Box 3)
    - Girard, Frank
      - 1965-1969 (Box 4)
      - 1972-1976 1982-1983 (Box 4)
    - Goodstein, Phil 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - Graham, Joseph (Box 4)
    - Gray, Bob 1974 (Box 4)
    - Graymont, Barbara 1977 (Box 4)
    - Hall, Donald 1975 (Box 4)
    - Hass, Eric
      - 1964-1966 (Box 4)
      - 1968-1970 (Box 4)
      - 1971-1976 (Box 4)
    - Holman, Tom 1979-1986 (Box 4)
    - Holmdahl, Lila 1977 (Box 4)
    - Horath, James (criticisms of Muncy speech) 1964) (Box 4)
    - Industrial Union Caucus in Education 1980-1982 (Box 4)
    - Johnson, Glen
      - 1966 (Box 4)
      - 1971-1977 (Box 4)
    - Jones, Bob 1981-1982 (Box 4)
    - Jones, Elwood 1974 (Box 4)
    - Kelly, Mary (Box 4)
    - Kelly, T.A. 1983-1986 (Box 4)
    - Lazarus, Daniel Bryan 1975-1976 (Box 4)
    - Lazarus, Louis 1974-1985 (Box 4)
    - Leech, Geoffrey 1986 (Box 4)
    - Lewin, Edward 1973-1978 (Box 4)
    - Long, Robert
      - 1967-1968 (Box 4)
      - January-February 1969 (Box 4)
      - March-July 1969 (Box 4)
      - December 1969-1971 (Box 4)
    - Lowy, Thomas (Box 4)
    - McGee, Peter Jr. (Box 4)
    - McGregor, Tom 1972-1987 (Box 4)
    - Members-at-Large 1970-1972 (Box 4)
    - Miller, Jeff 1972-1976 (Box 4)
    - Miller, Ronald 1980 (Box 4)
    - Minneapolis Chapter 1971-1972, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous (many to media)
      - Undated 1945-1969, 6 folders (Box 4)
    - Muncy, Ralph (correspondence while member of N.A.C.) (Box 4)
    - Muncy, Ralph (Box 4)
      (includes RM's notes accompanying the donation of his papers to the Bentley Library)
    - New York Chapter 1971 (Box 4)
    - Nielson, Amelia 1974 (Box 4)
    - Open letters to members 1960-1964 (Box 4)
    - Oslick, Alan 1968-1969, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Pataki, Ronald 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Perry, Benson (Box 4)
    - Peterson, Arnold (S.L.P. National Secretary)
      - January-October 1950 (Box 4)
      - November-December 1950 (Box 4)
      - 1951 (Box 4)
      - 1956-1968 (Box 4)
      - 1969 (Box 4)
    - Petrovich, Walter 1980-1981, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Philadelphia Chapter 1971 (Box 4)
    - Plant, James (English Socialist) (Box 4)
    - Pontiac Chapter 1970 (Box 4)
    - Powell, David 1982 (Box 4)
    - Prisoners 1974 (Box 4)
    - Quinn, John and Irma (Box 4)
    - Reyner, Jack (Box 4)
    - Reynolds, Dallas 1969, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Russell, Iain and Yolanda 1982 (Box 4)
    - Sallade, George 1970 (Box 4)
    - San Francisco Chapter 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Schwatrz, Simon 1972-1980, 1982 (Box 5)
    - Sim, Archie
      - 1962, 1968 (Box 5)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 5)
    - Sim, James (examples of failure to fulfill responsibilities) (Box 5)
    - Simon, Nick (see also Social Reconstruction corr. file)
      - Undated 1967 (Box 5)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 5)
      - 1970-1972 (Box 5)
      - 1972-1980 (Box 5)
    - SIUDB 1971-1972 (Box 5)
    - Smith, Charles 1985 (Box 5)
    - Smith, Robert 1975 (Box 5)
    - Southern California Chapter 1971 (Box 5)
    - Stevens, David 1979-1981 (Box 5)
    - Tompkins, Alan and Brenda 1971-1981; 1986 (Box 5)
    - Trent, Walter and Rose 1974-1986 (Box 5)
    - Tydesley, Michael 1975-1976 (Box 5)
    - Votano, Mary 1978-1980 (Box 5)
    - Weinstock, David 1972-1976 (Box 5)
- Topical files
  The Topical Files series relates to the activities and administration of the Socialist Labor Party, the Socialist Reconstruction Party, its successor, League for Socialist Reconstruction, and the Industrial Union Party. Each of these subseries includes notes, minutes, clippings, some correspondence, printed matter, and ephemera. In addition, the Socialist Labor Party subseries includes sound recordings of meetings, debates, and radio presentations. Again, the researcher should note the overlapping of files.
  - Socialist Labor Party 1928-1970
    - Activities 1950-1955 (Box 5)
    - Addresses and speeches
      - Undated, 3 folders (Box 5)
      - 1949-1958 (Box 5)
      - 1959-1970 (Box 5)
    - By-Laws, Membership material, etc. (Box 5)
    - By-Laws, Michigan Executive Committee undated (Box 5)
    - Cameron, Bruce (resignation) (Box 5)
    - Campaigns
      - 1928 (Box 5)
      - 1932 (Box 5)
      - 1938 (Box 5)
      - 1940 (Box 5)
      - 1944 (Box 5)
      - 1946 (Box 5)
      - 1948 (Box 5)
      - 1950 (Box 5)
      - 1951 (Box 5)
      - 1952 (Box 5)
      - 1956 (Box 5)
      - 1957 (Box 5)
      - 1958 (Box 5)
      - 1959 (Box 5)
      - 1960, 3 folders (Box 5)
      - 1960 (Libraries in Michigan) (Box 5)
      - 1961 (Box 5)
      - 1962, 3 folders (Box 5)
      - 1963 (Box 5)
      - 1964 (Box 5)
      - 1966, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - 1968 (Box 6)
      - 1968 (bills and accounts) (Box 6)
    - Party circulars
      - 1946 (Box 6)
      - 1947-1948 (Box 6)
      - 1956-1964 (Box 6)
      - 1967 (Box 6)
    - Contacts
      - Correspondence from
        - 1956-1959 (Box 6)
        - 1960 (Box 6)
        - 1961-1963 (Box 6)
        - 1964 (Box 6)
        - 1966 (Box 6)
        - 1967-1969 (Box 6)
      - Inquiries for party information
        - 1967 (Box 6)
        - 1968 (Box 6)
        - 1969-1970 (Box 6)
      - Name Lists (from National Office)
        - 1956 1958 (Box 6)
        - 1959 (Box 6)
        - 1960 (Box 6)
        - 1961 (Box 6)
        - 1962 (Box 6)
        - 1963 (Box 6)
        - 1964 (Box 6)
        - 1965-1966 (Box 6)
        - 1967 (Box 6)
        - 1968 (includes Muncy notes) (Box 6)
        - 1969 (includes Muncy notes) (Box 6)
      - Schools 1965 (Box 6)
    - Conventions
      - Constitutional 1961 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 6)
      - Minutes from State Conventions (Box 6)
      - Minutes from the National Conventions (23rd-27th) (Box 6)
      - 27th National Convention 1968 (Box 6)
      - 27th National Convention 1968 (drafts from) (Box 6)
    - Court Action against Senator Gillis W. Long 1956 (Box 6)
    - DeLeon Manuscript, First Draft (written after 1980) (Box 6)
    - Detroit Free Press Libel 1953 (Box 6)
    - Discrimination against minorities (Box 6)
    - Disruption within the party 1947 (Box 6)
    - Election information (Box 6)
    - Fairs
      - Contracts (Box 6)
      - Design of S.L.P. booth and interior furnishings (Box 6)
      - Evaluation of S.L.P. activities (Box 6)
      - Instructions to S.L.P. members (Box 6)
      - Insurance policies (Box 6)
      - Literature on S.L.P.
        - 1957-1959 (Box 6)
        - 1960-1961 (Box 6)
        - 1962-1968 (Box 6)
      - Michigan S.E.C. Committee (Box 6)
      - Michigan State Fair (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
      - Other fairs (Box 6)
      - Reports
        - 1958-1959 (Box 7)
        - 1960-1969 (Box 7)
    - Federal Communications Commission (Box 7)
    - Finances, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Financial statements 1954-1965 (Box 7)
    - Financial reports from National Office (Box 7)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign 1982 (Box 7)
    - Hass (Eric) censure (Box 7)
    - Hass (Eric) censure-Los Angeles section (Box 7)
    - History (Box 7)
    - Labadie Collection (U of M) 1954 (Box 7)
    - League of Women Voters
      - 1958-1959 (Box 7)
      - 1960-1963 (Box 7)
      - 1964, 1966 (Box 7)
      - 1968 (Box 7)
    - Lectures 1958-1968 (Box 7)
    - Membership cards (Box 7)
    - Membership 1962-1968 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Civil War Centennial Observance Committee 1963 (Box 7)
    - Michigan Executive Committee (M.E.C., Ralph Muncy-chairman) (Box 7)
    - Michigan Executive Committee (minutes) (Box 7)
    - Michigan State activities 1947-1950 (Box 7)
    - Michigan State Central Committee (Ralph Muncy, chairman see also topical S.L.P. reports)
      - Undated 1955-1969, 6 folders (Box 7)
    - Minutes, Section Washtenaw (Box 7)
    - Minutes, Section Wayne (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Muncy letter of appeal (Box 7)
    - National Executive Committee (N.E.C.) Session May, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Newspaper clippings
      - 1949-1952 (Box 7)
      - 1956-1961 (Box 7)
      - 1962-1970 (Box 7)
    - Organizer for party 1950-1951 (Box 7)
    - Party Literature 1953-1955 (Box 7)
    - Platforms of other parties (Box 7)
    - Press and Publicity
      - Letters to the editor, radio and television broadcasters
        - Ann Arbor News 1946-1991 (Box 7)
        - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation 1983-1986 (Box 8)
        - Detroit Free Press 1962-1965, 1982, 1989 (Box 8)
        - Detroit News 1962-1967, 1990 (Box 8)
        - Magazines 1962-1990 (Box 8)
        - Michigan Daily 1963-1967 (Box 8)
        - Newspapers, General 1951-1991, 2 folders (Box 8)
        - Open Letters 1962-1990 (Box 8)
        - Radio 1967-1991 (Box 8)
        - Television 1960-1991 (Box 8)
        - U. S. Farm News 1987-1988 (Box 8)
      - Press Releases 1953-1969 (Box 8)
    - Radio and television broadcasts
      - General 1946-1966 (Box 8)
      - Questionnaires sent out as result of radio and television broadcast (Box 8)
      - Youth Wants to Know (Socialist Smear) 1954 (Box 8)
      - Scripts
        - General 1952-1957 (Box 8)
        - Ann Arbor Cable Television (Box 8)
        - Radio address of Ralph Muncy, candidate for Congress 1962 (Box 8)
        - WPAG 1976 (Box 8)
        - Weekly People (radio programs) (Box 8)
    - Replies of S.L.P. Mailings Recipients 1954-1955 (Box 8)
    - Reports (see also M.E.C. & Michigan State Central Committee)
      - 1940-1951 (Box 8)
      - 1952-1962 (Box 8)
      - 1963-1965 (Box 8)
      - 1966-1969 undated (Box 8)
    - Reports 1957-1964 (Box 8)
    - Reports of Committees of Michigan Executive Committee (Box 8)
    - Senate Bill 1011 1954-1955 (Box 8)
    - Signature Gathering 1949-1955 (Box 8)
    - Social Events (Box 8)
    - Socialist Party of Ireland 1981 (Box 8)
    - State Conventions 1952-1955 (Box 8)
    - Study Classes (Box 8)
    - Study Class Outlines 1948 (Box 8)
    - Study Class (Section Washtenaw County) 1948-1949 (Box 8)
    - Textbooks (Box 8)
    - University Lecture Series/Speaking Engagements 1952-1954 (Box 8)
    - University of Michigan S.L.P. Club (Box 8)
    - Washtenaw Referendum 1969 (Box 8)
    - Washtenaw Resolutions 1968 (Box 8)
    - Weekly People (newspapers) (Box 8)
    - Weekly People
      - General 1953-1955 (Box 8)
      - Weekly People News Review 1953-1955 (Box 8)
  - Sound recordings (Box 9)
    - Recordings of meetings 1949-1964, 42 tapes; 7 in. 3 3/4 (Box 9)
  - Socialist Reconstruction (later known as League for Socialist Reconstruction) series
    - Branch activities
      - Branch Ann Arbor (B.A.A.) (Box 10)
      - Branch Bay Area (S.F.B.A., San Francisco) (Box 10)
      - Detroit Daniel DeLeon League Branch (D.D.L., Detroit) (Box 10)
      - Minneapolis Branch (Box 10)
      - New York Daniel DeLeon League Branch (Box 10)
      - New York Socialist Committee of Correspondence (S.C.C.) (Box 10)
      - Philadelphia Solidarity Branch (Box 10)
      - Branch Pontiac (Box 10)
      - Southern California League for Economic Democracy (S.C.L.E.D.) (Box 10)
    - Committee for Union Democracy Newsletter (C.U.D.-Mpls.) (Box 10)
    - Constitutions and Declarations (Box 10)
    - Conference
      - National
        - 1970 (see also I.C.C.) (Box 10)
        - 1970 (statements and other pamphlets) (Box 10)
        - 1971 (proceedings, voting) (Box 10)
        - 1971 (information, reports, etc.) (Box 10)
        - 1972 (Box 10)
      - Observers (Box 10)
    - Daniel DeLeon Publication (in Russian) (Box 10)
    - Dissension in Philadelphia spring spring 1972 (Box 10)
    - Dissolution of organization (includes balloting & final accounting) (Box 10)
    - Editorial Board (Box 10)
    - Fraternities and sororities (Ann Arbor) (Box 10)
    - Industrial Commonwealth Committee (pre social reconstruction group)
      - Undated correspondence (Box 10)
      - October 1969-June 1970 (Box 10)
      - July 1970-August 1970 (Box 10)
    - Interim Secretary (Box 10)
    - Lowy, Thomas (Executive corresponding secretary of Socialist Committee of Correspondence) (Box 10)
    - Magazine (Box 10)
    - National Administrative Council (N.A.C.)
      - General (Box 10)
      - Treasurer's Office (Box 10)
    - Newspaper Editors (letters to) (Box 10)
    - Philadelphia, Plunder proposals (Box 10)
    - Publications, policies (Box 10)
    - Publications, "Socialist Reconstruction" (rough draft) (Box 10)
    - Quarterly report (comments 1972) (Box 10)
    - Question Answer Pamphlet (Box 10)
    - Reaffirmation of branch members (Box 10)
    - Reconstitution of party 1972 (Box 10)
    - Referendums
      - 1970, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - January-May 1971 (Box 10)
      - June-December 1971 (Box 10)
      - 1971 (National Conference) (Box 10)
      - 1972 (Box 10)
      - Letters from National Secretary (Box 10)
    - Responses (to advertising and to resignations) (Box 10)